Mahmoud Ibrahim

Junior Android Developer

Cairo, Egypt | (+2) 01147104982 | mah.khalil22@gmail.com

Summary

Mobile Developer (Native Android & Flutter) and UI/UX Designer expert with expertise in the creation apps and management of UX designs and campaigns With extensive experience in the Android Studio, Flutter, Photoshop and Adobe XD. Lead the building process of new program development by managing all tasks and supervising the team of analysts and operators.

Experience

Android Developer Trainee - 07/2018 to 08/2018

Te-data, Smart Village

Build Native Android Apps using java and tools of Android SDK, Material Design, SQLite, Json, API, Postman, Retrofit, Shared Preference, Intent, Recyclerview, lifecycle, Android Permission, Google Maps, Firebase, etc...

Android Developer - 08/2019 to 10/2019

IntelliMinds, 6th of October City

Android Bootcamp with kotlin we learned how to build android app using kotlin and oop concept, Android Material Design, Android Layouts, Manifest, Gradle, Intent, Fragments, Recycelerview, Butterknife, Android Permission, Json, API, Postman, Retrofit, Design Architecture (MVC - MVP - MVVM), DataBinding, RxJava, RxAndroid, LiveData, Firebase.

Android Developer Nano-degree – 03/2017 to 05/2017 **Million Arab Coder, Udacity**

Course Android Nano-degree by Udacity and Final Exam.

Skills Highlights

- Java
- Kotlin
- Dart
- Flutter
- Android SDK
- Android Studio / VS Code
- Material Design
- SQLite
- ROOM
- REST APIs
- Retrofit Json
- Postman

- Firebase
- LiveData
- MVP MVVM
- RxJava2 & RxAndroid
- Google Maps
- Git/Github

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology: Computer Science - 2019

Misr University for Science and Technology, 6th of October City

Websites

linkedin.com/in/dev7odaa

github.com/dev7odaa

Projects

- **Top News**: is an android app get news from api and show trend news based on location and you can select what country you need to read leatest news and choose it.
- **WE Home**: Re-Build WE application in native code using java and using WE Api that i test it by postman and build ui from scratch and show data in different components of material design.
- Kotlin Calculator: Build kotlin calculator with own design of simple calculator and take of principle of material design.
- **3al-mashy**: android app take data from sqlite file of buses time & locations and represents it in listview and google maps.
- **Student Registration:** application take data of username and password from student and saves it in a local file on the device.